Christos Kapsalis

Full-Stack Software Developer | Software Engineer

xrikapsalis@gmail.com | +30 694 793 4771 | Athens, 16777, Greece <u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio</u>

Professional Summary

Full-stack software developer for 8+ years of hands-on experience across the entire development lifecycle. Front-end development in **React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), CSS3, Bootstrap** and **HTML5**. Back-end development in **Node.js, Java, Lua** and **PHP**. Eager to learn new languages, technologies and undertake interesting projects. Accountable, working on schedule and comfortable working as a team member.

Core Skills

Front-end Development: React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, Redux, PWA, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap **Back-end Development:** Node.js, Express.js, Next.js, Lua, Java, Spring Framework, PHP, SQL, Bash Scripting, C

DevOps & Deployment: Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins

Version Control: Git, SVN

Data Formats & APIs: RESTful APIs, JSON, AJAX, XML, SVI

Testing: Unit Testing, JUnit, Jest, Robot Framework

Development Tools & Others: VS Code, Eclipse, Phpstorm, Sublime, Codecharge Studio, SQL Clients, Postman, Browsers' Web Developer Tools, Balsamiq (Mock-ups), Wireshark, CMS, Agile

Work Experience

Freelance Climbing Instructor & Software Development Sabbatical

November 2022 - Present

- Providing climbing instruction on a freelance basis, focusing on safety and skill development for climbers of all levels.
- Pursuing advanced full-stack development training (Zero to Mastery Academy).
- Developing projects using **React.js**, **Node.js**, and modern web technologies.
- Maintaining and expanding technical knowledge during career transition period.

Senior Technical Specialist

Nokia | Athens

December 2021 – October 2022

- Developed back-end components of Altiplano Controller, an open software GUI platform connecting other Nokia's software units via **RESTful APIs**.
- Implemented **Java-based microservices** feature with **JUnit** testing, loaded on a **Docker** container and deployed on **Kubernetes** infrastructure.
- Managed PODs configurations and orchestrated software interactions within Kubernetes environment.
- Experience in Intent development logic, microservices, Cloud based solutions, DevOps operations, Kibana search engine and Postman request engine.

Software Engineer

Nokia | Athens

 $September\ 2016-December\ 2021$

- Full-stack development of WebCT (2016-2021), a software that provided a GUI to administer X-Haul microwave products. Led back-end development of WebCT in Lua and DB handling with Lua-Sqlite3.
- Implemented WebCT GUI in Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap framework.
- Side project development of ASLM (2018-2021), an app that produces licenses for all X-Haul products, in **Java** with **JUnit** testing in the back-end and **React.js** in the front-end.
- Involved with the full circle of a feature's production. Creation and reviewing of feature's code, software architectural designs, Low Level Design, mock-ups, CuDo documents. Developing at least one feature per release while following a biannual release schedule.
- Peer reviewing of Code, Use Cases, Test Strategy and Test Cases.
- Applied full stack Unit Testing and debugging of code.

Software Engineer

Nokia | Athens

June 2015 – August 2016

- Full-stack development of the FMANG application, a comprehensive monitoring and configuration management system for Nokia's FlexiNG product.
- Contributed to back-end development of new features released on a biannual schedule in **Java** and **Java EE Development toolset (JSF/Primefaces, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Tomcat, Jenkins, Junit)**, while maintaining code quality through peer reviews of code.
- Development of the front-end in JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Led complete GUI redesign initiative after company's rebranding and resolved with the help of the team a critical

system-wide bug affecting application stability.

E&V Tester

Nokia | Athens October 2014 – May 2015

- Managed CI Test Suite of 400+ test cases for Nokia's LTE network gateway (FlexiNG).
- Implemented automated testing using **Robot Framework** with daily CI reporting.
- Enhanced testing coverage by developing new test cases and improving existing ones.

Web Programmer/Developer

Cybertechnics Interactive Communication LTD | Athens

December 2012 - January 2014

- Full-stack development of Modus CMS using PHP, MySQL in the back-end and JavaScript, HTML and CSS in the front-end.
- Managed back-end administration and development of CMS' modules and components.
- Updating and debugging CMS' code and executed database operations, upon customers' requests.
- Implemented RAFM (Restricted Access File Manager) filesystem and integration of Ajaxplorer GUI into Modus CMS.

Education

Zero To Mastery Academy

zerotomastery.io

October 2024 – Present

Attending Full-Stack Web Developer Career Path. Updating my knowledge on **CSS**, latest versions of **JavaScript**, learning **React.js**, **Redux**, **PWA**, **Node.js** with **Express.js**, **PostgreSQL**, **Machine Learning API** by building web apps, incorporating all these technologies.

University of Piraeus

Piraeus

September 2004 – October 2011

University degree - Bachelor in <u>Digital Systems & Technology Education</u> | Computer Science

Stockholm University and KTH joint department

Erasmus Exchange Student Program | Knowledge Management

January 2009 - June 2009

Languages

Greek (Native), English (Fluent), Italian (Intermediate)